Guide to the Geneva Valentine papers, 1922-2008 MS2340
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Community, political, and legislative engagement, 1948-1971; Series 5; 2.25 Linear Feet
  Arranged alphabetically by organization, then by subject area.
  - Adams-Morgan Federation: correspondence and newsletters, 1968-1971; Series 5 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Adams-Morgan Federation: memos and reports, 1968-1970; Series 5 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Adams-Morgan Federation documents [1/5], 1969-1970; Series 5 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Adams-Morgan Federation documents [2/5], 1969-1970; Series 5 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Adams-Morgan Federation documents [3/5], 1970; Series 5 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Adams-Morgan Federation documents [4/5], 1970-1971; Series 5 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Adams-Morgan Federation documents [5/5], 1969-1971; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Adams-Morgan Federation zoning documents and correspondence, 1970; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Beautification Committee for Adams-Morgan correspondence, 1967; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Asbury Methodist Church documents [1/2], 1952-1971; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Asbury Methodist Church documents [2/2], 1963-1964; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Hollyday House: publicity and correspondence, 1955-1966; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Hollyday House documents [1/5], 1966-1969; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Hollyday House documents [2/5], 1966-1968; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Hollyday House documents [3/5], 1961-1968; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Hollyday House documents [4/5], 1965-1968; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Hollyday House documents [5/5], 1965; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Inspiration House: correspondence, photographs, and documents, 1948-1957; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Inspiration House: financial documents, 1949-1958; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Housing and Urban Development-related documents, 1967-1969; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Positive Action Against Crime documents, 1966-1970; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Community initiatives, including Metrorail, MC Terrell Fund, and relevant correspondence, 1954-1970; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Community initiatives: additional documents and correspondence, 1965-1970; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Political and legislative engagement: correspondence [1/4], 1968-1969; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Political and legislative engagement: correspondence [2/4], 1966-1968; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Political and legislative engagement: correspondence [3/4], 1955-1970; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Political and legislative engagement: correspondence [4/4], 1969-1970; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Political and legislative engagement: publications [1/2], 1950-1967; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Political and legislative engagement: publications [2/2], 1969-1970; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Family members of Geneva Valentine, 1940-1987; Series 6; 0.5 Linear Feet
  The materials of this series pertain to members of Geneva Valentine's family, namely her husband Hugh Valentine, Sr. and her son, Hugh Valentine, Jr. This series dates from 1940 to 1987 and includes financial documents and calculations, income tax forms, deeds, legal documents(including Hugh Valentine, Jr.'s marriage and divorce paperwork), correspondence, and real estate documents (including records of 2008 16th Street Inc. dating beyond Geneva Valentine's death). Also included in this series is a Resolution of Appreciation to Hugh Valentine Sr. from the National Geographic Society. This series is organized as close to chronologically as the original order and arragnements of its materials would allow. The papers of Hugh Valentine, Sr. are followed by the papers of Hugh Valentine, Jr.
  Arranged roughly chronologically.
  - Hugh Valentine Sr. papers [1/4], 1943-1968; Series 6 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Hugh Valentine Sr. papers [2/4], 1940-1942; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Hugh Valentine Sr. papers [3/4], 1959-1974; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Hugh Valentine Sr. papers [4/4], 1976; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Hugh Valentine Sr. Papers: Resolution of Appreciation to Hugh Valentine from National Geographic Society, 1962; Series 6 (Flat box 5, Item 1)
    Item is housed in Series 1, Box 5 with other oversize certificates
  - Hugh Valentine Jr. papers [1/3], 1973-1985; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Hugh Valentine Jr. papers [2/3], 1987; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Hugh Valentine Jr. papers [3/3], 1971-1987; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Hugh Valentine Jr. oral history, 2016 June 24; Series 6; 1 digital object(s)
    link to audio recording
    https://archive.org/details/hugh_valentine_oral_history